<idea-plugin>
    <id>nl.hicts.mph.plugin</id>
    <name>Maven Project Helper</name>
    <vendor url="https://github.com/mrhoeve/mph">MPH</vendor>

    <description><![CDATA[
        Manage versions, builds, dependencies, and Git synchronization across a Maven workspace from IntelliJ IDEA.
    ]]></description>

    <!--
        Release maintenance: update this section for every plugin release. Put the newest version first and describe
        user-visible features, improvements, and important fixes; IntelliJ renders it in the plugin's What's New tab.
    -->
    <change-notes><![CDATA[
        <h2>Initial IntelliJ IDEA release</h2>
        <p>
            Maven Project Helper brings multi-repository Maven workspace management directly into IntelliJ IDEA.
            It is designed for teams that develop many related services, libraries, parents, and modules together.
        </p>

        <h3>Workspace insight</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Discover linked Maven projects and modules from IntelliJ's Maven model.</li>
            <li>Inspect workspace-only dependencies and dependents, with direct navigation to their POM files.</li>
            <li>Explore an interactive dependency graph with project focus, zoom controls, and PNG export.</li>
            <li>Calculate repository build stages, identify cycles, and export the build order to Excel.</li>
            <li>Inspect searchable dependency trees and export CycloneDX SBOMs as JSON or XML.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Version management</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Update a project version together with references in dependent workspace projects.</li>
            <li>Apply or remove upgrade prefixes across multiple projects and realign linked versions.</li>
            <li>Update dependent projects directly from the POM editor context menu.</li>
            <li>Inspect managed version properties and coordinate Spring Boot upgrades.</li>
            <li>Read released versions from Git tags while respecting the local Maven and Git environment.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Build and Git workflows</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Build selected repositories or individual modules with configurable Maven options and live output.</li>
            <li>Open or build any project from the MPH tool-window context menu.</li>
            <li>View branch names and ahead/behind status for every repository.</li>
            <li>Create coordinated feature branches across multiple repositories.</li>
            <li>Synchronize upgrade branches with develop using stash, rebase, restore, and safe version realignment.</li>
        </ul>

        <h3>Security and supply chain</h3>
        <ul>
            <li>Run Nexus IQ evaluations for repositories and modules using existing Jenkins pipeline application IDs.</li>
            <li>Inspect policy violations, severity summaries, remediation guidance, and full Nexus IQ reports.</li>
            <li>Keep credentials in IntelliJ's secure password storage and reuse local Maven configuration.</li>
        </ul>

        <p>
            Thank you for trying the first IntelliJ IDEA release of Maven Project Helper.
            Feedback and issue reports are welcome on GitHub.
        </p>
    ]]></change-notes>

    <depends>com.intellij.modules.platform</depends>
    <depends>com.intellij.java</depends>
    <depends>org.jetbrains.idea.maven</depends>
    <depends>Git4Idea</depends>

    <extensions defaultExtensionNs="com.intellij">
        <notificationGroup
                id="Maven Project Helper"
                displayType="BALLOON"
                isLogByDefault="true"/>
        <toolWindow
                id="MPH"
                anchor="right"
                icon="/icons/mph.svg"
                factoryClass="nl.hicts.mph.intellij.ui.MphToolWindowFactory"/>
        <applicationConfigurable
                parentId="tools"
                instance="nl.hicts.mph.intellij.ui.NexusIqConfigurable"
                id="nl.hicts.mph.intellij.settings"
                displayName="Maven Project Helper"/>
    </extensions>

    <actions>
        <action
                id="nl.hicts.mph.intellij.UpdateDependentProjects"
                class="nl.hicts.mph.intellij.actions.UpdateDependentProjectsAction"
                text="Update Dependent Maven Projects…"
                description="Find linked Maven projects that reference this project"
                icon="nl.hicts.mph.intellij.icons.MphIcons.Mph">
            <add-to-group group-id="EditorPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
            <add-to-group group-id="ProjectViewPopupMenu" anchor="last"/>
        </action>
    </actions>
</idea-plugin>
